(回顾上集在成长的烦恼中)
(Previously on growing pains)
杰森:看起来你们的奶奶和,呃……
Jason: Yes it seems that your grandmother and, uh,
威利:威利.
Wally: Wally.
杰森:威利决定举行一个婚礼.
Jason: Wally, have set a wedding date.
奶奶:在一艘去加勒比海的游船上.
Grandma: On a cruise to the Caribbean.
迈克:不错的旅行.
Mike: Not a bad commute.
本:迈克,听这个.
Ben: Mike, listen to this.
奶奶:这个是什么?
Grandma: What's this?
杰森:哦,只是我让我律师写的一些东西.
Jason: Oh just a little something I had my lawyer whip up.
是些很简单的东西.
It's really very simple.
奶奶:标准婚前协议.
Grandma: Standard prenuptial agreement!
杰森:对对对.呃,我想当你看到它时第一反应肯定会反感,以后你会觉得这很明智……啊
Jason: Yep, yep, yep, yep.It's uh, and I think that as soon as you
get over your initial reaction, you are going to see the wisdom...ah
朱莉:迈克,我感觉现在和你走得很近.
Julie: I feel very close to you right now, Mike.
迈克:嗨,我们俩是很近.
Mike: Hey, we are.
迈克:朱莉:我是说认真的,我已经爱上你了.
Julie: I'm serious.I'm falling in love with you.
迈克:来吧.水正好.
Mike: Well come on in.The water's fine.
本:迈克,迈克,迈克,迈克,迈克,迈克,
Ben: Mike, Mike, Mike, Mike, Mike, Mike, Mike.You will not believe this.
迈克,迈克,迈克,你肯定不会相信的.今天是我们的幸运日.
Today is our lucky day.
迈克:为什么?是什么?
Mike: Why?What is it?
本:迈克,在这艘船上有20个世界上最辣的女孩子.
Ben: Mike, there are twenty of the hottest babes in the world on this boat.
迈克:怎么了.
Mike: So.
本:我是说20个瑞典女孩,金发,体操队的.
Ben: We're talking Swedish, blonde, gymnasts.
迈克:嗨,本,女孩子除了长相外还得具备些别的东西.我是说你得考虑很多其它事情比如,
Mike: Hey, there is much more to a woman than the way she looks.Alright.
个性,智商,还要呃,
I mean you got to take into account all kinds of things like her personality
还要她们的呃,呃,呃.我在说些什么?
and her intelligence and uh, and her uh,
迈克:这是我有生以来第一次同时被八只女人的手在我身上摸.
Mike: This is the first time in my life I've been touched by eight female
hands at the same time.
本:对我来说是第二次了.
Ben: Second for me.
迈克:哦,是谁呀……
Mike: Well hello...
朱莉:朱莉.
Julie: Julie.
迈克:朱莉,真有趣我……朱莉!
Mike: Julie.That's funny, I.Julie!
多琳:我想"演员艾维斯在船上的表演"是你们的婚礼节目之一?
Doreen: I understand "your ships Elvis impersonator" is part of the wedding.
艾维斯:是的.
Elvis: Yo.
杰森:哈哈哈.刚才我完全在想其他事情.你继续吧.
Jason: Ha ha ha.I was thinking of something else totally.Please go on.
威利:我不能再忍了.
Wally: I can't take this.
奶奶:或许你希望来个大赦.
Grandma: Well maybe you would like a pardon.
威利:或许我想要个直升飞机.
Wally: Well maybe I would like a helicopter.
奶奶:哦,你不用等直升飞机了.游泳吧!
Grandma: Well don't wait for the helicopter.Swim for it!
杰森:这就是我那份婚前协议想要预防的那种会出现的难以预料的情况.
Jason: This is exactly the kind of unforeseen situation;
prenuptial agreements are designed to protect you against.
迈克:本就在那儿.你知道我们的关系.
Mike: Ben's right over there.You know, our relationship.
朱莉:什么关系?
Julie: What relationship?
杰森:嗨,麦琪.门链怎么了?
Jason: Hey, Maggie.What's with the chain?
麦琪:给你.拿走你自己的东西.
Maggie: Here.Pack your own things.
杰森:怎么了.你不觉得太过分了一点吗?
Jason: What.Aren't you over reacting just a little?
麦琪:嘘!克莉丝刚刚睡着.你马上收拾东西因为我们今晚要换个房间睡.
Maggie: Shhh!Chrissy just got to sleep.You're packing because we need to do a little room switching tonight.
杰森:换房间?
Jason: Room switching!
麦琪:是的.你妈妈今晚要睡这.
Maggie: Yes.Your mother is sleeping in here tonight.
杰森:哦.我知道在排练时出了一点小事情……
Jason: Oh come on.I know the rehearsal went a little haywire...
麦琪:一点小事情?
Maggie: A little haywire!
杰森:嘘!克莉丝刚睡着.
Jason: Shh!Chrissy is asleep.
麦琪:杰森,我现在没法和你静下来进行一场有逻辑的对话.
Maggie: Jason, I'm too upset with you right now to have a logical discussion.
杰森:你从没静下来过.
Jason: It never stopped you before.
麦琪:威利屋子里有空床.
Maggie: There's room in Wally's cabin.
杰森:你说什么?让我和威利一块睡!
Jason: What?Me sleep with Wally!
麦琪:你会觉得比在这睡幸运多了.
Maggie: You'll have better luck than in here.
杰森:你把妈妈和威利之间发生的所有事情都怪到我的头上,对吗?
Jason: You blaming me for everything that happened between Wally and my mother tonight, aren't you?
麦琪:不,我没不怪你.我怪你那张邪恶的嘴.
Maggie: No, I don't blame you.I blame your evil twin.
杰森:好吧,麦琪.你说的对.
Jason: Ok Maggie, you're right.
麦琪:我当然对了.
Maggie: Of course I am.
杰森:我不能和你进行有逻辑的对话.
Jason: You are not capable of having a logical discussion.
麦琪:从你那个婚前协议出炉开始……
Maggie: From the moment you whipped out that prenuptial aggree...
杰森:哦!我没有出炉任何东西,
Jason: Oh I didn't whip out anything Maggie.
麦琪.让事实来证明吧.他们的吵架跟婚前协议毫无关系.
And let the record show, their fight was not about a prenuptial agreement.
麦琪:哈!
Maggie: Ha!
杰森:只要你愿意你尽管哈去吧!
Jason: Oh ha if you want to.
但是我告诉你婚前协议会是他们一生的保护者.
But I'm telling you that prenuptial agreements can be life savers.
我做的所有事情都是想保护我妈妈的财产.
All I was doing was trying to protect my mother's assets.
麦琪:杰森,在我说一些我会后悔的话之前,
Maggie: Jason, before I say something I regret, but enjoy,
我确实想说我们认为你是一个傻瓜!
let's consider for a moment that you are a complete loon burger.
(敲门)
(Knock at the door)
奶奶:请开门.
Grandma: Knock knock.
麦琪:嗨.
Maggie: Hi.
奶奶:嗨.
Grandma: Hi.
杰森:妈妈,好吧,我知道你很难过.但是请你想想,这事情现在发生总比以后再发生好吧.
Jason: Mum, ok, I know you're upset.But please, isn't it better that this happened now rather than later?
奶奶:说的对.哦,今晚会有很多趣事的, 就我们两个女人.
Grandma: Righty oh.This is going to be so much fun tonight, just us girls.
麦琪:哦,我知道.
Maggie: Oh I know.
杰森:心头的创伤正在慢慢进行治疗.
Jason: The healing process is already underway.
麦琪:杰森.我们为什么不去大厅谈呢!
Maggie: Jason.Why don't we talk in the hall?
杰森:好吧麦琪.我是懂理的人.
Jason: Come on Maggie.I'm a reasonable man.
我不知道我怎样才能把这说得更清楚些.一个人如果知道自己是对的,就不会在乎在哪里睡觉.
I don't know how I can say it any clearer than that.
嗨!威利.
A man who knows he's right doesn't mind where he sleeps.Hey Wally.
威利:杰森,我在军队里的时候是个拳击手.
Wally: Jason, when I was in the army, I was on the boxing team.
杰森:这我可不知道.
Jason: I didn't know that.
威利:是的.而且每次打完拳以后我都会觉得舒服些,
Wally: Yeah.And I always felt better after a fight,
因为我很能接受我的拳头较量出来的结果.
because I was able to get whatever ailed me out of my system through my fists.
杰森:是的,你这样也不算不正常.
Jason: Well you know that's not so unusual.
我有很多病人都告诉我他们只要有个人能……
A lot of my patients tell me that if only they had someone to...
威利:来吧来吧.
Wally: Come on come on.
杰森:威利,我知道你想发泄一下,但看看我们两个吧.
Jason: Wally, I know you want to let your aggressions out, but look at us.
你的年纪,我的年纪.这太不公平了.
You your age, I my age.It just wouldn't be fair.
威利:好吧,我只用一只手,另一只放在背后.
Wally: Ok, I'll put one hand behind my back.
杰森:等一会儿.我们在这件事情上应该成熟一点.本,你去把哪儿了?你还好吧?
Jason: Wait a second.We should just be a little adult about this.Ben, where have you been?How are you?
本:很好,我要去浴室洗澡.
Ben: Fine, but I have to go to the bathroom.
杰森:嘿,你不想呆几分钟跟你老爸说会话吗?
Jason: Hey, you don't have a second to talk to your old dad?
你到底去干什么呀?
What have you been up to?
迈克:嗨.
Mike: Hi.
朱莉:我没心情听你胡说.
Julie: I'm in no mood for your charm.
迈克:听着,朱莉.朱莉,听着.你应该知道我之所以和这些漂亮姑娘在一起是因为她们让我想到了你.我只是想跟你开个玩笑.
Mike: Look Julie.Julie look.You should know that the only reason I was with those beautiful women is because they remind me of you.I figured I'd try and open with a joke.
朱莉:你算了.
Julie: You would.
迈克:好吧.那我就说了.
Mike: Ok, look.I'll just say it.
这些瑞典姑娘,她们喜欢我,
The Swedish women, they like me,
但是你应该知道我现在可以和其中任何一个姑娘在一起,也许甚至是好几个姑娘,
but you should know that I could be with almost any one of those girls
她们不是很聪明,
right now, maybe even several of them,
因此我现在完全可以和她们快乐一会.但是不,
and they won't so bright so I could probably be having a great time right now.
不,我情愿和你呆在这儿.
But no, no.I picked to be here with you.
朱莉:迈克,你想说什么?
Julie: Mike, what are you trying to say?
迈克:朱莉,朱莉,朱莉.你难道没看到我情愿为你放弃什么吗?
Mike: Julie, Julie, Julie.Don't you see what I am willing to give up for you?
朱莉:哦!
Julie: Oh!
杰森:哦你碰到了一些和你同龄的男孩子?
Jason: Oh you met some guys your age?
本:不.
Ben: No.
杰森:不?
Jason: No.
本:是20个不会说英语的金发瑞典女孩.
Ben: Twenty blonde babes from Sweden who don't speak English.
杰森:吼.哈哈.你学会你爸爸的幽默感了.
Jason: Ho.Ha ha.He's got his dads sense of humour.
威利:这不值得学.
Wally: It's not worth it.
本:我们在一起游泳,玩水上排球比赛.我们玩得很高兴.
Ben: We're swimming and playing volleyball.We were having a blast.
杰森:本,上床了.快.嗨朱莉,你发生什么事了?
Jason: Ben, go to bed.Come on.Hi Julie.Now what's the matter with you?
朱莉:我心里有点难过.
Julie: Well I'm a little upset.
杰森:啊,是因为今天闹翻了的事?
Jason: Ah, is this about the breakup?
朱莉:你也知道这件事了?
Julie: You know about that?
杰森:当然了,我怎么会不知道.
Jason: Of course I know about it.
但是我认为你没有理由要感到难过.
But I don't think its any reason for you to be so upset.
朱莉:怎么会没有呢?
Julie: There's not?
杰森:你不会是被他们感染了吧?
Jason: Aren't you getting a little carried away?
朱莉:(哭)
Julie: (crying)
杰森:真是个敏感的女孩子.
Jason: Sensitive girl.
开萝尔:朱莉!
Carol: Julie!
朱莉:对不起,开萝尔,我没打算要吵醒你.
Julie: I'm sorry Carol, I didn't mean to wake you up.
开萝尔:你和迈克吵架了吗?
Carol: Did you and Mike have a fight?
朱莉:吵架.我告诉他……你知道我们俩的事了?
Julie: A fight.I told him to...You know about us?
开萝尔:朱莉,跟你说话的是个聪明希弗孩子.
Carol: Julie, this is the smart Seaver child you are talking to.
朱莉:我简直不敢相信.首先是你爸爸,
Julie: I don't believe this.First your father, and now you.
现在轮到你了.那我们俩为什么还要躲着你们呢?
I mean why the heck have we been sneaking around for?
开萝尔:我爸爸可不知道你和迈克之间的事.
Carol: My dad doesn't know about you and Mike.
朱莉:但是他刚刚在大厅里问我我们两个吵架的事情.
Julie: But he just asked me about our breakup on the hall.
开萝尔:朱莉,我所知道的唯一一件吵架的事情就是我奶奶和威利闹翻那件事.
Carol: Julie, the only breakup I know about is grandma and Wally's.
朱莉:哦.
Julie: Oh.
开萝尔:你说的吵架是谁和谁?哦.
Carol: What break up were you talking about?Oh.
朱莉:我很高兴这件事情过去了,他能那么自私,而又不成熟.
Julie: I'm glad this is over with.He can be so selfish and immature.
开萝尔:那可能是因为他一时糊涂了.
Carol: Well that's probably because he was confused.
我的意思是说他以前可从没和谁恋爱过.
I mean he's never been in love before.
朱莉:是什么让你认为他是在恋爱?
Julie: What makes you think he's in love?
开萝尔:和你认为他在恋爱的原因一样.
Carol: Same thing that makes you think he is.
杰森:满月了.怪不得这些女人都发疯了.
Jason: Full moon.No wonder women are crazy.
迈克和杰森:女人.
Mike and Jason: Women.
杰森:嗨!
Jason: Hey.
迈克:嗨!爸爸.
Mike: Hey dad.
杰森:迈克.你来这干吗呢?
Jason: Mike.What are you doing up?
迈克:哦呃,只是……散散步.
Mike: Oh uh, just taking a walk.
杰森:对,我也是得.今晚是个不太好过的夜晚.
Jason: Yeah, me too.Been kind of a rough evening.
迈克:哦,发生什么事情了?是不是有个女人误解了你一些事情然后朝你发了通脾气?
Mike: Yeah, what happened?Some woman misunderstood something you said and blew up at you?
杰森:对极了.你刚才在楼下吗?你听到了我和你妈妈的谈话?
Jason: Actually yes.You were downstairs?You heard your mum and I talking?
迈克:没有,爸爸,这真是个美丽的夜晚.
Mike: No.Dad, nice night.
杰森:出什么事了?
Jason: What's the matter?
迈克:没什么.
Mike: Nothing.
杰森:算了迈克.我是你爸爸.嘿,到底怎么了?
Jason: Come on Mike.I'm your father.Hey, what's going on?
迈克:哦,我不能告诉你.
Mike: Look, I can't tell you.I wish I could but I can't.
我希望我能跟你说但是我不能.再见了爸爸.谢谢!
I'll see you later dad.Thanks.
杰森:好吧好吧.如果你不想跟我说的话你就不要说.我尊重你的隐私.
Jason: Ok fine fine.You don't have to tell me if you don't want to.I respect your privacy.
迈克:爸爸,我真的需要和你谈谈.
Mike: Dad, I really need to talk to you.
杰森:谈什么.是什么事情?
Jason: What?What is it?
迈克:哦,是这么一回事,爸爸.我和一个女孩约会有一段日子了.
Mike: Well see dad, I've been going out with this girl for quite a while.
杰森:啊!
Jason: Ah!
迈克:但是现在我们已经结束了.
Mike: But it's over now.
杰森:哦!她是谁?
Jason: Oh!Who is she?
迈克:朱莉.
Mike: Julie.
杰森:哈哈哈.好了,你在开玩笑是吧.不要逗了.你不是在开玩笑吧?
Jason: Ha ha ha.Right.You're kidding.Come on.You're not kidding are you?
迈克:不.没有,爸爸,我没开玩笑.
Mike: No.No dad I'm not.
杰森:那么这件事情发生多久了?
Jason: Well how long has this been going on?
迈克:四个月.
Mike: For four months.
杰森:四个月了!我还以为她肯定会受不了你呢.
Jason: Four months!I thought she couldn't stand you.
迈克:她是不能.
Mike: She can't.
杰森:这些都是在我鼻子底下发生的事?
Jason: This has been going on right under my nose?
迈克:对,但是这再也不会发生了,
Mike: Yeah well it's not going on anymore,
就因为她看到我和一些女孩子在一起玩.
and just because she caught me flirting with a few girls.
杰森:什么女孩子?
Jason: What girls?
迈克:二十个金发的瑞典女郎.
Mike: Twenty blonde Swedish women.
杰森:嗨,这船上真的有二十个金发的瑞典女郎吗?
Jason: Hey, they are twenty blonde Swedish women on this boat?
迈克:对.
Mike: Yeah.
杰森:我怎么就没看见呢.
Jason: I am losing it.
迈克:对,我是犯了个小错误.就算这是个大错误吧,那也不能意味着一切就此结束吧.
Mike: Yeah so I made a little mistake.It was a huge big humungous mistake, but that shouldn't mean that this whole thing is over.
杰森:我错失了看见二十个金发瑞典女郎的机会?
Jason: I missed twenty blonde Swedish women?
迈克:是的.有一天我会觉得二十个瑞典女郎对我来说是不是太多了一点.
Mike: Yeah.And there was a day when twenty women would be three, four more than I would ever need.
杰森:嗨,你记得有一次我到你房间里去的事吗?我说"迈克,我刚才好像听到朱莉的声音了",你说"不,不会的,爸爸.那只是你的幻觉".你那是在……
Jason: Hey remember that time when I was up in your apartment?Remember, I said "Mike, did I just hear Julies voice" and you said "No, no dad.That's just your imagination".Are you telling me that...
迈克:她躲在我的浴室间里.
Mike: She was hiding in my bathroom.
杰森:我知道.那么你为什么要对保守这么大的一个秘密?
Jason: I knew that.So why do you want to keep this such a big secret?
迈克:哦,
Mike: Well, you know.
是这样子的.朱莉是给你和妈妈干活的,
With Julie working for you and mum,
所以她认为如果你们发现她和我在……我永远也不会得到了.
and she thought that if you found out about me and her...
我只知道和朱莉一起出去玩是我感到的一件最最快乐的事.
I never got it myself.
当我和她在一块的时候我很喜欢这种感觉.
All I know is that going out with Julie has been the best thing that has
你知道,爸爸,
ever happened to me.I don't just like her.I like me when I'm with her.
我不想我们就这样结束了.
You know and dad, I don't want this to end.
杰森:哦,
Jason: Well you know the pressure to keep this thing a secret has got
你知道保守这个秘密对你来说会造成很大的压力.
to create a big strain on you.
迈克:事实上我们这样躲来躲去很有意思.
Mike: Well actually it was kind of fun sneaking around.
杰森:好了.如果你们能得到我的祝福,
Jason: Come on.Wouldn't it have been a lot more fun if you'd have had
这不就更有意思了吗?
my blessing?
迈克:不!
Mike: Nah!
杰森:迈克,好了.
Jason: Mike, come on.
不管你有没有意识到,
Whether you realize it or not,
父母和子女在潜意识中都希望彼此能够相互理解.子女真正需要父母的理解,
the subconscious desire for approval between a parent and a child is crucial.
而父母也确实需要子女的理解.
A child really needs a parent's approval;
那就是原因.所以我一直都是个傻瓜.
a parent even needs a child's approval.That's why.I've been a boob.
迈克:我听懂的只有最后那句话.
Mike: All I understood was the last point.
杰森:我真不敢相信……我做了些什么?解铃还需系铃人.
Jason: I can't believe...what have I done?Physician heal myself.
迈克:等等.我没系过铃.我需要你更多的帮助.
Mike: Wait a minute.I'm not a physician.I need more help than that.
杰森:哦,我在说我自己的问题.
Jason: Well I'm talking about my problem.
迈克:那我的问题呢?
Mike: What about my problem?
杰森:你照其他人做的做就行了.你在她面前跪下来求她原谅她认为你做过的事情,因为你可能做过.就算你真的没做过也没什么关系因为只要你有爱那么受点委屈也不算什么.
Jason: You just do what men have always done.
You get down on your knees and you beg for forgiveness for whatever it
is she thinks you've done wrong, cos you probably done it.
And if you didn't do it then it doesn't matter anyway cos as long as you
are in love, you are never going to get a fair shake.
迈克:这就是你的好建议?
Mike: That's your great advice?
杰森:迈克,你应该学会自己思考了.
Jason: Mike, you're old enough to finally be told.
你生活中的最大乐趣就是……做些荒唐事.
The things you enjoy the most in life...make no sense whatsoever.
迈克:等一等.你要去哪里?
Mike: Wait a minute.Where are you going?
杰森:我要让你的奶奶和威力重归旧好.
Jason: I've got to go and get gran and Wally back together.
迈克:什么?他们闹翻了?
Mike: What they broke up?
但是他们明天早上就要结婚了!
But they are supposed to be getting married tomorrow morning!
这对我来说倒真的有点荒唐.
This makes no sense to me whatsoever.
杰森:你学的可真快.
Jason: You're leaning.
迈克:你说什么?我学到些什么了?
Mike: What?What am I learning?
杰森:妈妈,妈妈.让我进来.我知道有点晚了,但我们还是谈谈好吧.妈妈.
Jason: Mum.Mother.Let me in please.I know it's late, but we have to talk.Mum.
麦琪:杰森,怎么了?
Maggie: Jason, what's the matter?
杰森:是我.
Jason: Me.
奶奶:亲爱的,什么事?
Grandma: Honey what is it?
杰森:我是个大傻瓜.
Jason: I've been a total jerk.
奶奶:是的,这我早就知道了,亲爱的.
Grandma: Well yes I know that dear.
杰森:我要祝福你和威利的婚姻.
Jason: You have my blessing to marry Wally.
奶奶:我不想和威利结婚.
Grandma: I don't want to marry Wally.
杰森:你们要结婚.
Jason: Yes you do.
奶奶:不,我不结了.
Grandma: No I don't.
杰森:妈妈,问题的关键是,我是曾经反对你和威利结婚,但是自从爸爸死后无论你和谁结婚我都会反对.这个问题总是缠着我使我身上好像有股邪劲.我想威利是个好人而且我越来越喜欢他了.
Jason: Mum, look the point is, yes I've had my problems with you marrying Wally, but I'd have my problems with you marrying anybody after dad.And those problems have had me all tied up and I've been acting like my evil twin.I think Wally is a good man and I know in time I could grow fond of him.
奶奶:哦,那么你和他结婚好了.你听到今晚他和我说话的口气了吗?
Grandma: Well then you marry him.Did you hear the way he talked to me tonight?
杰森:是的,但是那些话并不是对你说的.那是冲着我说的.
Jason: Yeah but that fight wasn't about you mum.It was about me.
奶奶:不,不是那样的.
Grandma: No it wasn't.
杰森:是那样子的.妈妈.
Jason: Yes.Mum
奶奶:不,不是我.杰森,我不想因为我们讨论我和威利闹翻的原因而再跟你吵一架.
Grandma: Don't it wasn't me.Jason, I'm not going to fight with you about why I had a fight with Wally.
杰森:你们之所以吵架那都是因为我在惹你们生气.让我们面对一切吧,
Jason: That fight happened because I was being irritating.
有时我确实挺让人讨厌的.
Now let's face it, sometimes I can be a little irritating.
麦琪:孩子,这点你说对了.
Maggie: Boy that's right.
杰森:哦,如果你安静几分钟的话,这儿没人会把你当哑巴.
Jason: Oh, so you're quiet for a few minutes and this is your contribution?
麦琪:杰森,我只是表示同意你的观点而已.
Maggie: Jason, I was just agreeing with you.
奶奶:杰森,甚至在你很小的时候,
Grandma: Jason, even when you were little,
你就能把你爸爸和我气的发疯.
you could drive your father and me up the wall.
杰森:是的.如果连你们这么深爱我的两个人都受不了,
Jason: Yes.And if I can do that with two people who love me,
那么可怜的威利怎么受得了我呢?
imaging how crazy I'm driving poor Wally.
奶奶:哦,我想他甚至连见都不想见我了.
Grandma: Oh, I'm sure he doesn't even want to see me.
杰森:那么,妈妈,给他个选择的机会吧.
Jason: Well then mum, don't give him a choice.
威利:婚前协议.这跟那个家伙有什么关系?
Wally: Prenuptial agreement.What's the matter with a guy like that?
我把我自己搞成了一个傻瓜.
Here I make a fool of myself...
奶奶:威利!
Grandma: Wally!
威利:厄玛!你在那外面干吗?,你会摔死你自己的.
Wally: Urma what are you doing out there?You're going to kill yourself.
奶奶:我们得谈谈!
Grandma: We've got to talk.
威利:谈什么?
Wally: What?
奶奶:我们两个得谈谈!
Grandma: We have got o talk.
威利:哦,我,我,我,我,我……
Wally: Oh, well, wh wh wh wh...
奶奶:这样谈我们是谈不清楚的,亲爱的.
Grandma: We are not off to a very good start dear.
威利:哦,厄玛.今晚我的表现就像个傻瓜.我真的很抱歉.
Wally: Oh Urma.I acted like a chump tonight.I am so sorry.
奶奶:不威利,你做得对.
Grandma: No Wally, you were right.
威利:我做对了?
Wally: I was right?
奶奶:是的.这是你和我以及我们俩共同生活的事情.
Grandma: Yes, it is about you and me and our life together.
我早就该这么跟你说了.
I should have told you then.
威利:那么我的表现不像个傻瓜了?
Wally: Then I didn't act like a chump?
奶奶:当然有点了,亲爱的,但这不是你的错.
Grandma: Of course dear, but it was not your fault.
杰森才是真正的大傻瓜,他现在已经明白了,他已经为我们两个祝福过了.
Jason was the real chump and he knows that but he's given us his blessing.
哦,我知道这根来没什么关系但是还是那样想了,那么就让我们一切重新来过吧.
Oh I know it shouldn't matter but it does, so let's start all over again.
威利:我可不想让你再重复那些话了.那只会让我越听越糊涂.
Wally: I won't ask you to repeat that.It would only confuse me.
奶奶:你还记得你是在哪向我求婚的吗?
Grandma: Do you remember where you proposed to me?
威利:当然记得了.就在那边那个阳台上.
Wally: Of course.On that balcony right over there.
奶奶:那儿看起来似乎是个重新开始的好地方
Grandma: Seems like a good place to restart.
威利:肯定就是的.
Wally: Sure does.
奶奶:啊!
Grandma: Ahhhh!
威利:厄玛!厄玛!
Wally: Urma!Urma!
迈克:哦,你差点让奶奶摔死了.
Mike: Way to go dad.You just killed grandma.
奶奶:我没有受伤.
Grandma: No harm done.
威利:厄玛!厄玛!你还好吧?
Wally: Urma!Urma!Are you alright?
奶奶:是的,我很好.
Grandma: Yes, I'm fine.
威利:你吊在那根绳子上干吗呢?
Wally: What were you doing hanging from that rope?
奶奶:哦,我只是想让这一刻具有戏剧性.
Grandma: Well I just wanted the moment to be dramatic.
威利:哦,这已经够戏剧性的了.
Wally: Well it was dramatic alright.
奶奶:那么,我们刚才说到哪儿了?
Grandma: So, where were we?
威利:我给忘了.
Wally: I'm not sure.
奶奶:哦,我们说到我们在同一个阳台上,
Grandma: Well we're on the same balcony,
同一个满月下,同样美好的夜晚.
under the same full moon as it was that wonderful night.
威利:我肯定我们也穿着同样的浴衣.你知道吗厄玛.我还记得那晚我说了些什么.我从来没有那样爱过别的人,我想和你一起走过我剩下的日子.
Wally: And we are in the same bathrobes I believe.You know Urma.I remember what I said that night.I never loved anybody more and I want to spend the rest of my life with you.
奶奶:哦,亲爱的.我也爱你.你记的那晚你还对我说了些别的什么吗?
Grandma: Oh honey.I love you too.You remember what else you said to me?
威利:哦,哈哈哈.
Wally: Oh, ha ha ha.
奶奶:不,我说的不是那个.
Grandma: No, I mean afterwards.
威利:我希望马上和你结婚.
Wally: That I want to marry you right now.
奶奶:哦,可是没有什么在阻止你啊.
Grandma: Well what's stopping you?
迈克和杰森:喔!
Mike and Jason: Woo hoo!
麦琪:朱莉,开萝尔,快起床!
Maggie: Julie, Carol, wake up!
开萝尔:发生什么事了?
Carol: What's the matter?
麦琪:你奶奶和威利现在就要结婚了.
Maggie: Your grandma and Wally are about to get married.
开萝尔:现在?
Carol: Right now?
迈克:快起床.
Mike: Get up.
本:啊!
Ben: Ahhh!
迈克:快走.
Mike: Let's go.
麦琪:人都在这了,船长!
Maggie: Everyone's here captain.
杰森:那么我们就在这儿举行婚礼吧!
Jason: Well let's get this show on the road.
船长:那个就是搞砸了整件事的人吗?
Captain: Is that the one that messed everything up?
多琳:大家站好.你们还记得排练的时候自己站的位子吗?
Doreen: Okee dockee.Does everyone remember their places from rehearsal?
奶奶:哦,我们正尽力把那件事给忘了.
Grandma: Oh well we are trying our best to forget that.
威利:我们可以把这件事情了结了吧?
Wally: Can't we just wing it?
多琳:哦,鲍勃,我可不想半夜把自己从床上拉起来就为了了结这事.
Doreen: Oh look Bob.I didn't drag myself out of bed in the middle of the night just to wing it.
船长:让我们来做个了结吧.
Captain: Let's wing it.
开萝尔:即使我们要了结这事,我们也应该做得隆重些.这些是花.
Carol: Well even though we are winging it, we can still do it right.Here's the bouquet.
多琳:哦,我忘了拿盒式录音机了.
Doreen: Oh I forgot the cassette recorder.
没音乐我们怎么能弄好婚礼呢?
We can't have a wedding without music.
所有人:开始了.
Everyone: Wing it.
艾维斯:当当当当,当当当当.祝福你们.当当当当,大家一起来.
Elvis: Dum dum dee dum.dum dum dee dum.Mercy.Dum, dum, dee dum, everybody.
所有人:当当当当.
Everybody: dum dum dee dum, dum.
杰森:嗨,停停.我来行吗?
Jason: Hey stop.May I cut in?
奶奶:当然行了!哦.
Grandma: Sure.Oh.
杰森:艾维斯.
Jason: Elvis.
艾维斯:当当当当,当当当当.
Elvis: Dum dum dee dum, dum dee dum dum dee dum.
船长:尊敬的各位,因为我是船长,
Captain: Dearly beloved, because I am the captain,
而且因为我很累了,所以婚礼得快一点.
and because I am very tired, this wedding will go very quick.
迈克:朱莉,我想和你谈一会!
Mike: Julie, I've got o talk to you for a second.
朱莉:好吧.
Julie: Yeah.
迈克:嗨,朱莉,我真的很抱歉,我早就该对你老实坦白了,我不应该给我所做的事情找任何借口.我想我当时是糊涂了.我以前可从没有爱过人.
Mike: Hey look Julie, I'm really sorry and I should have just been honest with you before and told you that I have no excuse for what I did.I guess I was just confused.I've never been in love before.
朱莉:你是在和我恋爱?
Julie: You're in love with me?
迈克:哦,是的.
Mike: Oh yeah.
瑞典女孩:我们听说这里有舞会.
Swedish girls: We heard there was party.
本:就是现在.快进来一起来.
Ben: There is now.Come on in.
船长:你希望他做你的合法丈夫吗?
Captain: To be your lawful wedded husband.
奶奶:是的.
Grandma: I do.
迈克:你相信我是吗?
Mike: You believe me don't you?
朱莉:是的.
Julie: I do.
船长:因为我是船长,所以我现在宣布你们结婚了.
Captain: And because I am the captain I now pronounce you husband and wife.
新郎现在可以吻新娘了.
Kiss the bride.
朱莉:我爱你迈克.
Julie: I love you Mike.
迈克:我也爱你.
Mike: I love you too.
多琳:厄玛,你应该扔你的花了.
Doreen: Urma Overmyer, you have to throw your bouquet.
奶奶:好,准备.
Grandma: Ready.
瑞典女孩:哦!
Swedish girls: Ohhhh!
本:风得到了那些花.那些花它们下不来了.别管它姑娘们.姑娘.
Ben: The winds got it.That thing is never coming down.Forget it girls.
嘿!我怎么样!谢谢你了奶奶.
Girls.Hey!What about me!Thanks a lot grandma.
多琳:亲爱的,哦亲爱的,哦亲爱的.
Doreen: Dear, oh dear oh dear.
杰森:威利,我希望你能原谅我.
Jason: Wally, look I hope you'll forgive me.
我想说的是,
I just would like to say that, well you know yesterday that prenuptial thing,
昨天那个婚前协议,我感到很抱歉.
I'm sorry.
威利:哦,呃,没什么.我会给房钱的.
Wally: Oh, uh, it's ok.I'll still pay for your room.
杰森:好.
Jason: Yes.
迈克:嘿,嘿,看!
Mike: Hey, hey look!
威利:哦,看那.多美啊!我的天!
Wally: Oh look at that.Isn't that gorgeous?My gosh!
朱莉:是很美.
Julie: It's beautiful.
杰森:你也很美.
Jason: So are you.
威利:你也很美.
Wally: So are you.
迈克:你也很美.
Mike: So are you.
本:她们也很美.
Ben: So are they.
迈克:我有句话要说.
Mike: I've got something I'd like to say.
奶奶:好吧,说吧迈克.
Grandma: Well go ahead Mike.
迈克:首先我要感谢我的爸爸妈妈,
Mike: First I'd like to thank mum and dad and grandma Urma and Grandpa
和厄玛奶奶威利爷爷,你们让我们明白了爱情和婚姻是多么的伟大.
Wally for showing us all how great love and marriage can be.
现在我有个惊喜要给大家.
And I've also got kind of a surprise for everybody.
杰森:哦,等等,你们听他说.
Jason: Oh, wait till you hear this.
麦琪:你知道他要说什么?
Maggie: You know what's coming?
杰森:对.我没有什么不知道的.
Jason: Yeah, nothing gets by me.
迈克:我要让你们大家都知道,我要让整个世界都知道,
Mike: I want you all to know, heck I want the whole world to know,
我爱朱莉.我要她做我的妻子.
that I love Julie Costello.And I want her to be my wife.
麦琪:你们都知道这件事?
Maggie: You knew about this?
杰森:呃.
迈克:什么?
00:21:46,200
Jason: Uh. Mike: Well?